# 剛剛看到這裡有一條好大的蜈蚣啊
I just saw an enormous centipedes here.
# 哇 看到啦 在這裡
Wa! I see it now. It’s here.
# 夠大條吧你看 這個蜈蚣很危險的哦 這個
It’s huge isn’t it? This centipedes is really dangerous, you know.
# 咬一下人很痛的
It hurts like hell if you got bitten.
# 剛好這裡還有 一口酒 倒下去
It just so happens that here are, some last few drops of wine. Let me pour it inside.
# 蓋子 要先那個蓋子來
The cover, I need the cover first.
# 啊 快點 喝點酒
Ah! C’mon! Drink some wine!
# 這個酒很好喝的 蓋起來
This wine tastes really good. Cover it up!
# 它一下子
Instantly,
# 沉在酒色當中
it has lost itself in debauchery.
# 給它喝點這個酒
Let it drink some of this wine.
# 這個酒可以泡著用來做那個的
It can be infused in it and make the, you know...
# 它很喜歡這裡哦
It likes this place so much.
# 泡個半個月 它就 那個味道就出來啦
Leave it here for a fortnight. Then it, the flavour will be coming out.
# 好不好玩 這裡
Is it fun here?
# 把它放在家裡 我要乾活啦
Let me leave it here. I gotta start working.
# 幹活之前要補充點能量
Before I start working, I need to refuel myself.
# 吃點這個 然後再來上山
Let me have some, this one. And then I’ll go onto the hill.
# 嗯 好香
Um! It smells so good!
# 燙皮
“Tang pi” (local snacks)
# 小狗 你們要不要
Puppies! You want some?
# 搞一點點給它
Let me give it a bit.
# 誒 會吃哦
Eh? He’s eating.
# 你要嗎
You want it?
# 要你就說啊 你又不說 我怎麼知道你要
Tell me if you want! How can I know that you want it if you don’t tell me?
# 好不好吃
Does it taste good?
# 好吃就要說啊
You gotta tell me if it tastes good.
# 你看 上癮啦 這個 這個很香的呦
Look! He can no longer resist. It, it smells really good, you know.
# 我去把上面那個魚塘把它放啦
I’m gonna go up there, and drain the ponds.
# 那個魚塘我放了好多魚下去的哦
I’ve put a lot of fish into the ponds, you know.
# 都快養了一年啦 應該也大啦
They have been there for almost a year. They should have grown up now.
# 全是蛇頭魚 跟那個鯰魚
All are snakehead fish, and also the, the catfish.
# 你看 那個羊肉包在那裡哦 偷窺我們
Look! The Lamb Bun is over there, peeping us.
# 小羊
Goaty!
# 我去抓魚你去不去
I’m gonna catch some fish. You wanna join?
# 哦 它們在這睡覺
Oh! They’re having a nap here.
# 你看 那兩條豬在這裡哦
Look! Those two pigs are here.
# 跟著那大豬在睡大覺
They’re having a big sound sleep with the big pig.
# 你們就好咯 天天不愁吃不愁穿的
I envy you so much. You never need to worry about your meals and your clothes.
# 還要我餵你
You just ask me to feed you.
# 我們不幹活就飯飯吃啦
We simply wouldn't have our share of meal if we don’t work.
# 你看 把這個草都快讓它們鋤完了
Look! They’ve almost cleared all the weeds here.
# 到時候我們直接種點象草 很靚的哦
I'll then plant some elephant grass here right away. It would be really beautiful, you know.
# 不聽話啦 現在
It’s so naughty now.
# 一 一來它就跑 以前它都很聽話的
It, it runs away once I get close. It used to be a very good piggy.
# 現在都不聽話了
But it’s so naughty now.
# 你看那小豬 它又去那裡 泡澡啦
Have a look at that piggy. It’s over there, taking a bath again.
# 生活過很好滋潤啊 我們又給它取了個名字
What a wonderful life! We’ve also given it a name.
# 把它叫作那個 紅燒肉
It’s called, well, Stewed Pork.
# 那小豬 黑豬 那個黑豬叫紅燒肉
The piggy, black pig, that black pig is called Stewed Pork.
# 下次我一叫紅燒肉它就馬上過來啦
It would come immediately whenever I call “Stewed Pork” next time.
# 我要餵的時候 餵的時候那個要 先喊一下它的名字
When I feed it, when I feed it, I gotta, you know, first call its name.
# 餵多幾次它自然 我一來一叫它 它就馬上過來啦
Feed it a few more times, then, whenever I come, I call it, it would come immediately.
# 紅燒肉
Stewed Pork!
# 紅燒肉 過來
Stewed Pork! Come here!
# 沒反應 還不知道 剛起的名字
No response. It still doesn’t know. It’s a new name.
# 慢慢的就習慣啦
It will get used to it.
# 這兩個白的也給它們起了名字
We have also given names to these two white ones.
# 叫 叫豬大腸
They, they’re called Chitterlings.
# 一個豬大腸A 一個豬 豬大腸B
One is Chitterlings A. The other is Chit, Chitterlings B.
# 反正兩個嘛 兩兄弟
Afterall, they’re, well, brothers.
# 不要哦 應該是兩夫妻
Ah no! They should be a couple.
# 一個A 一個B好區分
One is A, one is B. Then there’s a difference.
# 我去上山上那裡抓點魚
I’m going onto the hill and catch some fish.
# 這裡我去年放的魚 今年不知道有沒有
These are the fish that I put last year. But I’m not sure if they’re still here this hear.
# 前兩天我看到有魚在那裡的
I came here a couple of days ago and saw that the fish were still there.
# 在那動 不知道多大的魚
They were moving. But I don’t know how big that are.
# 哇 全部長草啦 這裡
Wa! Here, the weeds are growing everywhere.
# 全部都是草
The weeds are everywhere.
# 你看 這裡還有個雞窩哦 被我清的差不多啦
Look! Here’s a roost. I’ve almost cleaned up this place.
# 到時候再蓋個棚子 我買隻雞放在這裡面
I just need to build a shed here later. Then I can buy a chicken here,
# 讓它自由生長
and let it grow freely.
# 你看 剛才我看到那魚在動哦
Look! It just saw that fish moving.
# 不知道甚麼魚
But who knows what kind of fish it is.
# 把這個掀開一下 然後再直接把水舀乾
Let me take this one away, and then scoop up all the water right away.
# 放在這個溝 從這排出去 那個水
I pour it into the pit here, and let it flow away this way. I mean the water.
# 把這個放出去
Let me put it aside.
# 靠在這裡
Lean it here.
# 把這個水搞乾
I’m gonna drain all the water here.
# 肯定有大魚 這裡
Here, must be big fish.
# 剛剛看到它動了一下
I just saw it move a bit.
# 兩下就沒水啦
I can drain it in a second.
# 這個不知道會不會有魚 放在這裡
I’m not sure if here are any fish. Place it here.
# 我把它
I wanna,
# 套一下 不然那魚都跑掉了
trap them. Otherwise the fish might run away.
# 這個兩下就搞乾啦
It would be drained in a second.
# 哇 這個怎麼那麼深
Wa! Why is this one so deep?
# 這邊這個 這邊這個
The one here, the one here,
# 這邊這個快乾啦 真的
the one here will soon be drained. Really
# 誒 這邊這個
Eh? The one here,
# 那麼淺啊
why is it so shallow?
# 三個井都是連通的 我撈一下看撈不撈到魚先啊
These three wells are connecting each other. Let me see if I can catch any fish.
# 這個有大魚這裡
Here’s a big fish, here!
# 失算了 那麼深
I didn’t expect it. It’s so deep.
# 明天我帶抽水機過來
I’ll come again tomorrow with my water pump.
# 一下就把它抽乾
It would be drained in a second.
# 那麼深
It’s so deep.
# 而且全都是那個樹枝擋著了這裡
What’s even worse is that the branches are all blocking here.
# 現在也到底了
I can reach the bottom now.
# 誒 魚嘞
Eh? Where are the fish?
# 活要見人 死要見屍啊
C’mon! Fish! Dead or alive!
# 這裡差不多從這裡那麼深
It’s almost that deep here.
# 誒呦
Eyo!
# 有一條
Here’s a fish.
# 抓到一條那個鯰魚
I've caught a catfish.
# 抓到一條 還有的
So one. There should be more.
# 我記得放了兩條下去
I remember putting two there.
# 沒啦
No more.
# 就好像就一條
It seems to be just one.
# 放了兩條下去
But I’ve put two.
# 就剩這一條了
Now only one remains.
# 可能被它吃掉了
Perhaps it was eaten by the other one.
# 你看 蛇頭魚
Look! Snakehead fish
# 有啦 又撈一條蛇頭魚
Yea! One more, a snakehead fish
# 你看 這裡 撈到一條蛇頭魚
Look! Here, I’ve caught a snakehead fish.
# 放到桶裡面去
Put it into the bucket.
# 搞了兩條 這兩條就夠大啦
So we’ve caught two fish. These two fish are really big, aren’t they?
# 明天要把水抽 抽乾 看下有沒有
I’m gonna drain, drain the ponds tomorrow, and see if there are any more fish.
# 肯定有的 我放了那麼多條下去 就只剩下兩條啦
Certainly there are more. I’ve put so many fish there but now only two remain.